# **Daniel Mwaniki**

Software Engineer with 2+ industry experience and determined about solving real world problems through technology. Leveraging analytical competencies and attention to detail in order to deliver efficient solutions. View my two deferent portfolios (here or here)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Umeme networking solutions,** Thika — *Software developer* August 2021 - PRESENT

- Liaised with a creative team of engineers and project managers to build applications for the company's customers to access the services seamlessly
- Collaborating in developing the house automation systems(software's that will communicate with the sensors,
   Cameras, switches), that will create market for the company,
- Collaborating in designing their web based systems.

## Kenyatta University, Nairobi — intern

August 2021 - Dec 2021

 Leveraged my knowledge in hardware, ICT administration, troubleshooting, networking and web development to assist the students as well as the lectures handle day to day issues with computer appliances.

# **Hash Analytics,** Nakuru — data analyst intern

June 2020 - August 2020

Got to acquaint myself with skills regarding machine learning, artificial
intelligence and data analytics. In terms of data analytics a got a chance to
learn how to use data visualization tools such as python(Numpy, pandas.
Math plot-lib, sea born), tableau and tensor flow Worked on automated
data reduction and evaluation, solved Attrition problems.

## **Avats properties,** Nakuru — Software Developer

(Apprentice)

June 2020 - Sep 2020

- Collaborated in building a platform to make company's loan management easy and convenient for customers or the company easy access to loans,
- Worked on their web based systems that improved consumers a lot.
- Created their database and integrated it with the application, while also performing data entry for the project

## SKILLS

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, Php.
- Frameworks: Django, Node-JS, Laravel, Micro python.
- Libraries: Numpy, ScipyScikit-learn, Tensor-Flow, Keras, PyTorch, Pandas, Mat plot-lib, Beautiful Soup, Scrappy
- Tools: Git, REST API, AWS, Anaconda navigator, tableau ,mqtt
- Databases: SQL(Postgresql, MySQL, Mango-dB)



Nairobi, Kenya



+254 702 247 235



mwaniel03@gmail.com



Daniel mwaniki



linkedin.com/in/mwaniki-daniel/



github.com/mwaniel

## **EDUCATION**

# **Gretsa University,** Thika — BSc. Computer

Science

May 2017 - Dec 2021

Relevant Coursework: Distributed Systems, Data

Structures & Algorithms, Database Management, UI &

UX development and Compiler Construction

# Huawei Academy, HCIA-AI

April 2020 - July 2020

A course, powered by Huawei, that develops the skills needed to learn machine learning algorithms/model and gain skills in building them.

## Achievers College, web development

Dec 2016 - June 2017

A course, that develops the skills needed to build web applications and gain skills in building them.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Top-tier writers** — web app

Contributed in building a scalable application to enable clients to make interactions with the company. I leveraged laravel and MySQL database

#### **Big bytes**— catering

Developed a web site for booking catering services. I leveraged php. Html. css. Currently hosted at <a href="https://bigbytesltd.uk/">https://bigbytesltd.uk/</a>

**Mukirity**— *listings all the shops around customers* and *linking them with the merchants* 

I developed an Ecommerce system to enable Customers to find the shops easily and shop with them online,

The system allows multiple vendors to sell items in one platform. Currently hosted at <a href="https://mukiriti.com/">https://mukiriti.com/</a>

### **PUBLICATIONS**

## Getting started with numpy and pandas -- blog

Sept 2020 <a href="https://medium.com/@mwaniel03">https://medium.com/@mwaniel03</a>

It is a publication about pandas and numpy and how one can acquaintance him/herself with learning the basics